Scientists dug a hole to the bottom of
Antarctica, and they pulled up this ice
core, and it shows our atmosphere from
800,000
years ago. They dug it up right here,
where it's so cold that the ice just
piles up and up and up, trapping bits of
history inside, creating layers like
this that can be counted like tree
rings. But what's most interesting is
each of these layers is full of bubbles
that hold all sorts of gases from that
period's atmosphere. So every layer is
like a time capsule. And once a core is
pulled up, researchers carefully slice
it and then crush or melt it in vacuum
to prevent contamination. And this
releases those ancient gas bubbles so
they can analyze them, which is how they
made this chart showing how levels of
CO2 in our atmosphere have changed over
time. And then, in 2025, they pulled up
one that goes even farther, 1.2 million
years. To see that, subscribe.